<Document>
# Klovnstation rules

  Klovnstation prides itself on maximising player agency, but there are still some basic rules you have to obey in order for everyone to have fun. However, our bans are either unappealable short cool-off bans or unappealable permabans, so unless you do something unfathomably bad you will most likely never be banned for too long.
  This is the only rule document.

  Space Station 14 is not like most games. Many rules are designed to require roleplay, and not all rules are intuitive. Please take the time to read and understand the rules before you play so that you aren't surprised. Some of our rules are zero tolerance rules, meaning that a violation will result in an indefinite ban without any warning. Game admins will treat you as if you have read the rules, even if you have not.

## CORE RULES

  - Use English, lest you be adminabused.
  - Do not abuse LOOC or OOC, lest you be adminabused.
  - No sexual content. There could be kids here and I am not doing age checks, so if I see anyone ERPing they are getting permad.
  - Metacomming is very gigachad but please do not use them too abusively, such as talking when you are dead and whatnot. Since we lack an option to enforce this, this is basically an appeal to your good will.
  - If you cheat, you will get banned for a while to cool off or mercilessly abused by the admins.
  - Do not be a weaselly pilpul rules lawyer.

## IN-GAME RULES
  - Cyborgs must obey their laws familiars their masters, et cetera. Cool-off ban if not obeyed.
  - Do not fuck with arrivals and do not cause irreparable round ending damage to the station within the first 15 minutes. Cool-off ban if not obeyed.
  - Mindshield implants strip traitor status as an alternative to outright round removal by the now unleashed gigachad powergamer security. Please obey the fact that you are no longer a traitor.
  - Mindshields force you to obey the security and command ruleset
  - Antags must be friendly to their team. Security + command must try to keep the station running for as long as possible and the population as high as possible. Read the next section if you want to play these roles. This is due to the power these rules wield and the rarity of an antag drop. Cool-off ban if not obeyed.
  - Try to do your job. This is again a gentlemen's agreement.
  - Keep RP to at least the bare minimum. Do not use internet speak in communication.
  - Borgs' HUD tells them who is crew.
  - Do not ram shuttles into the station as a non-antagonist. This is temporary and will be removed once we fix this via gameplay.

# Command and Security rules

  You, as command or sec, have three goals. Keep the shift going for as long as possible, keep as many people alive as possible, and keep the station advancing along its gameplay curve.
  To achieve these goals you have been given extremely potent equipment and supreme authority.

  ## Point number one: keep the shift going
  This is simple enough. Repair damage, prevent harm and in general try to keep the station in the same condition as it was roundstart or even better (if someone decides to improve it).
  If you ascertain that damage repair is beyond your capability or the amount of dead is beyond recovery, then you are to call evac. You can call evac when the sentiment of the station crew is overwhelmingly for it as well, but you should try to make sure that it isn't.

  ## Point number two: Keep people in the round
  This is the most important point. If you behead 2 assistants just because they were being detrimental to the station that is 2 people out of the round. This is simply to prevent the admins needing to spawn many ghost roles. While we try to leave you as much freedom as possible, understand that you are the IC equivalent of us preventing needless round removal.
  You have been given tools to prevent RR. Here are some of them:

  ### Borging
  Cyborgs have to obey their laws, lest they get banned. By making people into cyborgs you keep them in the game and disallow their fuckery.

  ### Projects
  Nothing gets people together more than a fun project to do. Announce a stationwide project, say a shuttle build, and get problem players to work on it.

  ### Parole equipment
  This applies especially well with the station AI present. Something like an electropack linked to a button can shut down people when they start to cause problems. Do not be afraid to use the jail system. Most people actually change their mind after 10 minutes or so in the brig.

  ### Mindshield
  Mindshield implants are your most powerful tool. They force people to obey the same ruleset as you do. If the station works well and has a lot of money, you will be able to use mindshields to prevent the worst of the worst from fucking the station up. Remember, acting against mindshield is ahelpable.

  ## Point three: Let the station advance
  This is closely intertwined with point two, but let me reiterate: a station with no engineering, scientific, service or cargo projects is BORING! It is not fun to play on such a station.
  The job of you and sec is to make sure the people that want to advance can. See to it that new technologies are researched and fun projects are greenlit. Clown wants a conveyor belt hell across the station? Let him, and give him the resources. You never know when you will be able to use it say for moving crates or gas cans.
</Document>
